# **Bio-Data of Project Guide**

#### DEEPA KRISHNAN

M. Tech (Information Security)

S1, Plot #79/80, SreeVenkataLakshmi Nilayam,

Madhava Nagar Miyapur, Hyderabad, Telangana-500049 **Mob**: +91 9773423043 **email:** deepakrishnan84@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY:**

Post graduate in Information Security having 8 years experience in teaching graduate and post graduate level students and with high level of expertise in Network Security and Computer Networks. Authored research papers which have featured in reputed journals and has initiated and guided research projects with colleagues and students. Key areas of interest include Wireless Networks, Cloud Computing, Data Analytics and Big data and Distributed Computing.

EXPERIENCE: 8 years

# Assistant Professor, Dept of Information Technology B.V. Raju Institute of Technology, JNTU, Hyderabad Academic theory sessions for M.Tech and B.Tech students

#### Assistant Professor, Dept of Information Technology

Dec 2011 - Aug 2011

#### Pillai Institute of Information Technology, Media Studies and Research Centre, Mumbai University

- > Set up the Information and Network Security lab
- Lab-In Charge of IT Lab
- Project guide for undergraduate Computer Engineering and Information Technology course
- Special Topic Seminar guide for Undergraduate courses
- ➤ Handled theory and Practicals of Information and Network Security and System Security Course
- Mentor for College level Technical Paper Presentation Contest
- Interview Panel Member for Selecting Candidates for Masters Program

#### **Lecturer (Computer Science, Information Security)**

Jan 2008 - May 2009

#### Amrita Vishwa Vidya Peetham, Kerala, India

- Instructor for various Graduate and Under Graduate for computer science courses like System Software and Operating Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Organization and Architecture
- Designed course program and determine the evaluation policies and coordinating the question paper setting.
- University mentor and student guide for E-Commerce Course.

# Lecturer (Computer Science)

Jan 2006 - Jan 2008

#### Sree Buddha College of Engineering, Kerala University

- Lecturer for Computer Organization and Architecture, Multimedia Systems.
- Lab Instructor for C and C++ programming, Data Structures and Algorithms and Computer Organization and Architecture

#### OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE:

1 year

### Teaching Assistant Jul 2010 – Dec 2010 SRM University, Chennai

- Handled laboratory and tutorial sessions of Network Security for 1st year M. Tech students
- Volunteered and coordinated various university and department level conferences and workshops

# Trainee Researcher at Resource Centre for Cyber Forensics (Symbian, C#, Android)

Jan 2011 – Jun 2011

# CDAC (Gov of India's Center for Development of Advanced Computing)

Internship

- Proposed agent based forensic data extraction and analysis process and model for Symbian phones as part of the comprehensive Smartphone forensic tool
- > Developed a smart phone forensic application for Symbian phones.
- Documented various Smart Phone OS capabilities and vulnerabilities
- Presented research finding at AICERA 2011 International Conference

#### **EDUCATION:**

Qualification / Year	University/ Board/ Institute	CGPA/ Percentage
M. Tech ( Masters in Information Security & Computer Forensics)	SRM University, Chennai, India	9.57 / 10
2009 – 2011	State on verolog, chemia, maia	<i>5.57 / 10</i>
B. Tech	Cochin University, Kerala, India	71
2001- 2005	Cocinii Oniversity, Keraia, india	/ 1
<b>AISSE CBSE</b> [11 <sup>th</sup> - 12 <sup>th</sup> ]	SN Central School, Kerala, India	83
1999 – 2001	Siv Central School, Kerala, India	0.5
AISSE CBSE [10 <sup>th</sup> ]	CNI Control Colored Woodle Lind's	00.0
1999	SN Central School, Kerala, India	88.8

# IT SKILL SET:

Languages:	C, C++, C#.NET, ASP.NET, Java, JavaScript, HTML5
Database:	Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle
Operating System:	Windows 7, Windows 2003, Linux
Networking Tools:	Cisco Packet Tracer, Network Simulator 2.34, Qualnet Simulator, PeerSimP2P Simulator, IP Traffic Test and Measure(ZTI), Net Disturb Impairment Emulator Software for IP Networks(ZTI), ZTI LAN Traffic Version 2.7 Traffic Generator for IP Networks, CloudSim
<b>Computer Forensics:</b>	Network Session Analyzer, Email Tracer, Cyber Check Suite, EnCase Enterprise Edition
Design Tools:	Visual Studio 2012
Training/Courses:	Certified Ethical Hacking Version 8 by EC Council Valid till August 2016  CompTIA Security Plus Valid from July 2013 to 2016  Cyber Criminology at University of Madras  Workshop on Effective Research Paper Writing by IIT Bombay  Certified Cloud Computing Engineer by Innobuzz Knowledge Solutions
	Certified Information Security Expert by Innobuzz Knowledge Solutions  Workshop on IBM Cognos BI tool at TCS Powai

#### **RESEARCH WORK:**

Paper Publications:	Deepa Krishnan, "A Distributed Intrusion Detection system for Mobile Ad hoc Networks using tamper evident Mobile Agents", ICICT 2014, Published in Elsevier Procedia Computer Science, www. sciencedirect.com
	Deepa Krishnan, Madhumita Chatterjee, "Cloud Security Management Suite-Security As a Service", October 30 – Nov 2 <sup>nd</sup> 2012, WICT 2012, Trivandrum, India, Proceedings in IEEE Explore
	Deepa Krishnan, Madhumita Chatterjee, "An Adaptive Intrusion Detection System for Cloud Computing Framework", SNDS 2012, Trivandrum, India, October 11-12, 2012. Proceedings in Springer Recent Trends in Computer Networks and Distributed Systems Security ISBN: 978-3-642-34134-2 (Print) 978-3-642-34135-9 (Online)

	Deepa Krishnan, Satheesh Kumar S, A.Arokiaraj Jovith, "Symbian Phone Forensics-An Agent based Approach", AICERA 2011, Published in International Journal of Scientific and Engineering Research Volume3 April 2012
Membership of	The Indian Society for Technical Education Life Member (Membership No: LM 83949)
<b>Professional Bodies:</b>	The Computer Society of India (Membership No:01174929)
	The Cryptology Research Society of India (Membership No: L/5737)

Date: Signature